## DIRECTOR, SYSTEMS UNIT- BUSINESS ANALYST 3 Summary

Versatile Information Technology and Operational Manager with 14 years experience in the strategic planning, development and maintenance of an agency portfolio of over a dozen information and communication systems. Successful leader possessing extensive experience in daily operational support to over 200 direct users, oversight of logistics, equipment, network, telecommunications, security, and disaster planning, as well as application support to over 4000 users statewide and the public.

## Highlights

- Expert Liaison between Business Managers and IT
- Team Building/Leadership
- Staff Motivation and Development
- Project Planning/Management
- Event Planning/Management
- Large-Scale Systems and Projects

- Operations and Change Management
- Continuity of Operations Planning
- Contract Management
- Risk Management
- User Service Desk Management
- Data Collection, Analysis, Reporting and Publication

## Accomplishments

- Directed a team of 9 Business Analysts in the collaborative development of an innovative statewide child welfare information system, which implemented over 22 new legislative initiatives and received the Center for Digital Government award in 2015.
- Spearheaded the Continuity of Operations, Disaster Planning efforts for the Commonwealth's 24/7/365 ChildLine and Abuse Registry, resulting in approved, comprehensive state and federal plans.
- Negotiated, designed and implemented a secure, off-site back up Disaster Recovery location for the ChildLine and Abuse Registry.
- Hired, supervised, motivated, mentored and developed over 30 state and contracted business analysts, program specialists and support personnel over a period of 14 years.

### Experience

01/2010 to 12/2015

Director, Systems Unit- Business Analyst 3 State Of Idaho - Jerome, ID

Managed program and operational oversight and support of Agency portfolio of over a dozen information and communication systems. Supervised nine state and contracted business analysts and program specialists. Collaborated with service providers, citizens, county, state and federal partners. Defined strategy for the support of ChildLine and Abuse Registry operations, to include the telecommunication reporting system, staff logistics and equipment, and Continuity of Operations and Disaster Recovery Plans. Coordinated and oversaw staff resources needed to implement and support business and system changes, review of technical system documentation, functional specifications for system development and enhancements, test planning and management, user training, system documentation and analysis of user and/or system problems. Interpreted and conveyed state and federal mandates, regulations, policies, standards and objectives to ensure that current and future information systems collected the necessary data in compliance with mandates. Monitored contracts to ensure services were consistent with contract language and comply with federal and state requirements.

#### 01/2002 to 01/2010

Director, Information and Data Management Unit-Program Specialist Supervisor Comm. Of PA, DHS, Office Of Children, Youth And Families (OCYF) - City, STATE

Oversaw the development, maintenance, creation and implementation of management information and communication systems. Supervised a team of six Program Specialists. Collaborated with program staff, county, state and federal partners in the creation of federal planning documents, as well as the review, approval and monitoring of county child welfare Information Technology budgets. Managed the design, analysis and layout of outcome and program information provided through agency information system reporting, hard copy and website publications which included newsletters and state and federal data reports.

#### 08/1998 to 01/2002

Human Services Program Specialist Comm. Of PA, DHS, Office Of Children, Youth And Families, Bureau Of County Programs - City, STATE

Developed and implemented policies, standards and procedures relating to the implementation of statewide information systems. Researched, developed and enacted policies and procedures for requirements gathering, system design, testing, user support and policy and program review. Drafted Requests for Proposals and Federal Advance Planning Documents. Created the agency child welfare newsletter as well as introduced collaboration tools, such as SharePoint, which significantly saved time in project management and collaboration.

# Education

Project Management Commonwealth Office of Administration, Office of Information Technology - City, State

Certificate: Project Management Training PMI Springhouse Training Program - City, State

Project Management Fundamentals Peak Solutions - City, State

Managing a Project Using MS Project Commonwealth Office of Administration, Office of Information Technology - City, State

Managing Technical Contracts State Information Technology Consortium - City, State

Developing High Functioning Teams University of Pgh., Child Welfare Training Program - City, State

Managing for Results University of PGH, Child Welfare Training Program - City, State

Certificate: Incident Command System FEMA Emergency Management Institute

Pennsylvania State University - City , State Harrisburg Area Community College - City , State

Bachelor of Science Shippensburg University - City , State

Skills

MS Office, MS Project, Team Foundation Server, MS Test Manager, Visio, SharePoint